A Guide to the Papers of Homer Stille Cummings, ca.1850-1955
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- SERIES XV: LEGAL CASE FILES (POST ATTORNEY GENERAL YEARS) ca. 1939-1956
  - State of Connecticut vs. Harold Israel n.d. (Box 324)
  - Ernest Jacqua 1942 (Box 324)
  - Jefferson Electric Co. 1954 (Box 324)
  - William Johnson 1944-1952, 4 folders (Box 324)
  - Judd Family 1952-1955 (Box 324)
  - David E. Langrock 1954 (Box 324)
  - John S. Lawrence 1944-1945 (Box 324)
  - Re: Wildon Lloyd 1947 (Box 324)
  - Joe Lowe Corporation 1949 (Box 324)
  - U.S. vs. Henry Lustig 1949 (Box 324)
  - Walter Maguire 1947 (Box 324)
  - Andrew Makarchuk 1945-1946 (Box 324)
  - Marital Deduction under the Federal Estate Tax 1951 August (Box 324)
  - J.H. Marsman 1946 (Box 324)
  - Menominee Tribe of Indians vs. United States ca. 1944 (Box 324)
  - Sara Mae Miles 1954 August-October (Box 324)
  - National Federation of American Shipping 1945 (Box 324)
  - National Pneumatic Co., Inc. 1944, 1951-1952 (Box 324)
  - O'Donnell vs. O'Donnell 1942, 1945 (Box 324)
  - Oil Tanker Case 1954-1955 (Box 324)
  - U.S. vs. Paramount Pictures, et al. 1935, 1938 (Box 324)
  - Pendleton Iron Ore 1953 (Box 324)
  - Costica Popa 1949 (Box 324)
  - Public Power & Water Company 1954 August (Box 324)
  - Radio Voice of New Hampshire 1952-1954 (Box 324)
  - Remington Rand vs. Isabel Dysort Buch, et al. 1954 (Box 324)
  - Reade Shirts 1951-1952 (Box 324)
  - Albert L. Reeves 1953 (Box 324)
  - Residential Clinics 1955-1956 (Box 324)
  - Rock Creek Park ca. 1953 (Box 325)
  - Rollins College 1943-1948 (Box 325)
  - Rollins College 1943-1948 (Box 326)
  - U.S. vs. Joseph Rutkin, et al. 1943 (Box 326)
  - Henry Sanderson - Wills 1934, 1945, 1946 (Box 326)
  - Alvin E. Sandroff, et al. vs. U.S. 1946 October (Box 326)
  - Schering Corporation 1945 (Box 326)
  - Philip Schleit vs. Cummings, Stanley, Truit & Cross 1949 (Box 326)
  - Re: Warren L. Schryver 1945-1955 (Box 326)
  - U.S. vs. Michael Shapiro, et al. 1951 (Box 326)
  - James D. Smith Estate 1952, 1955 (Box 326)
  - Re: Morton Sobell 1953, 1956 (Box 326)
  - Wilbur Stammler (Box 326)
  - Supreme Court Arguments 1941-1948 (Box 326)
  - Re: William Tegtmeyer 1951, 1953 (Box 326)
  - Re: Emmanuel Thebner 1942, 1943 (Box 326)
  - Re: Montgomery Ward Thorne 1954 July (Box 326)
  - Turkish Railway Administration vs. Vulcan Iron Works 1953, 1955 (Box 326)
  - Re: David M. Ulman 1945, 1951 (Box 326)
  - Van Norstrand vs. Vapor Heating Company 1955, 1956 (Box 326)
  - Oil Case Transcripts 1915 (Box 327-330)
  - Source Files for Federal Justice by Homer Stille Cummings & Carl McFarland ca. 1750-1938 (Box 326)
- SERIES XVI: CERTIFICATES 1887-1947
  - Certificate of Oney Carstarphen's appointment as Surveyor General of Colorado 1887 January 24 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate from Buffalo Training School 1888 June 1 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings Bachelor of Philosophy degre from Yale University 1891 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings award of membership in the Kent Club, Yale Univesity 1893 June 27 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings law degree from Yale University 1893 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission to the Connecticut State Bar 1893 June 28 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission to the New York State Fair 1907 November 6 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate to practice law in the Southern District Court of New York 1914 November 16 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission as Attorney and Counselor of the U.S. Supreme Court 1915 December 6 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate to practice law in the Eastern District Court of New York 1922 May 3 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings honorary law degree from Rollins College, Florida 1924 February 26 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings honorary law degree from Oglethorpe University, Georgia 1934 May 27 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Cecelia Cummings certificate of appointment as aide-de-camp to the Governor of Kentucky's staff 1935 May 9 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings Doctor of Humane Letters degree from Lincoln Memorial University, Tennessee 1935 June 3 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings honorary degree, Marshall College, New Jersey 1935 June 11 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission to the Bar of the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia 1935 December 12 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings "Doctor of Oratory" degree from the White House Correspondents' Associatin 1937 June 28 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings honorary law degree from pennsulvania Military College, Pennsylvania 1938 June 7 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Resolution of Esteem presented to Homer Stille Cummings by the Bar Association of the District of Columbia upon his retirement as U.S. Attorney General 1939, 2 items (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission as Attorney and Counsellor in the United States Customs Court 1940 April 9 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certificate of admission as Attorney and Counsellor of the United States Court of Appeals, Washington, DC 1940 June 18 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings appointment as an Elector for the President and Vice-President of the U.S., for the State of Connecticut 1940 December 13 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Wedding certificate of Homer Stille Cummings and Julia M. Alter, Cockeysville, Maryland 1942 July 13 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Certification of the results of the balloting by the Electors of the State of connecticut (Homer Stille Cummings was an Elector) for President and Vice-President of the U.S. 1944 December 18, 2 items (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Homer Stille Cummings certification as a Benefactor of the Holy Land, granted by the Commissariat of the Holy Land, Franciscan Monastery, Washington, DC 1947 September 26 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Memorial booklet presented to Homer Stille Cummings by the Federal Bar Association n.d. (Box-folder 70:3)
- SERIES XVII: POLITICAL CARTOONS 1933-1945
  - "The Explanation Courteous," by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1933 August 24 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Wouldn't It Be Awful if they Got Away with Uncle!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1933 August 25 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Another Hoardin' Problem," by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1933 September 28 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Go Get Some Gold, Buddy, and I'll Take You On!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1933 (Box T1-T3)
  - "It's All Clinkered Up and Needs Cleanin!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1933 (Box T1-T3)
  - "he's Undoubtedly a Human Flea and Strong for Disarmament!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1934 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Certainly Looks Like the Big Ones Somehow Get Away" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1934 (Box T1-T3)
  - "And From reports It's Going to be Much Colder!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1934 (Box T1-T3)
  - "William Tell Overture" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1937 April 6 (Box T1-T3)
  - "I Thought You Looked Him Up!" by by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1937 September 16 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Nothing Wrong With Selling Those Democratic Boosk, Bertie, But We Ought to Fix It So It Won't Happen Here Again," by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1937 December 29 (Box T1-T3)
  - "The Constitution Is What the Attorney General Says It Is!" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1937 (Box T1-T3)
  - "One Is a Very Important Position" by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star 1937 (Box T1-T3)
  - "Go Get 'Em Mr. Cummings," by A.C. Warfel, St. Louis Post Dispatch 1937 (Box T1-T3)
  - "General Cummings, Cliff Says Here's That Election Wager Cartoon -- He Thinks You're a Chiseler -- You Could Just as Easily Bet Six Termas as Three," by C.K. Berryman, Washington Evening Star1945 March 4 (Box T1-T3)
- SERIES XVIII: MISCELLANEOUS 1792-1950
  - Photograph of two pages of letterbook of Edmund Randolph 1792-1795 (Box T1-T3)
  - Photograph of intial entry in the official copybook of William Wirt 1817, 2 items (Box T1-T3)
  - Graph of conditions in Germany and Austria-Germany in World War I n.d. (Box T1-T3)
  - Blueprints of property owned by Homer Stille Cummings in Stamford, Connecticut 1923, 1929 (Box T1-T3)
  - Maps of the travels of Homer Stille Cummings and Cecilia Cummings 1931 (Box T1-T3)
  - Certificate of Homer Stille Cummings' appointment as Attorney General 1933 March 4 (Box T1-T3)
  - Promotional placard for Federal Justice by Homer Stille Cummings and Carl McFarland 1937 (Box T1-T3)
  - Letters of Homer Stille Cummings and Franklin Delano Roosevelt re: Homer Stille Cummings' resignation 1938 December 23 and 31 (Box T1-T3)
  - Letter from Franklin Delano Roosevelt to Harold Stephens re: a dinner for Homer Stille Cummings 1939 January (Box T1-T3)
  - Reproduction of Vasari's portrait of Lorzenzo dei' Medici n.d. (Box T1-T3)
  - Reproduction of Pontormo's Portrait of Cosimo dei' Medici n.d. (Box T1-T3)
  - Banner with political buttons and badges ca. 1900-1950 (Box T1-T3)
  - Pen (with certificate) used by Franklin Delano Roosevelt in signing an act which created twenty additional federal judgeships, presented to Homer Stille Cummings 1938 May 31
  - Pen (with certificate) used by Franklin Delano Roosevelt in signing the Federal Juvenile Delinquency Act, presented to Homer Stille Cummings 1938
  - Photograph of testimonial dinner to Leo A. Rover 1934 February (Othertype 10)
  - Photograph of dedication of the Department of Justice Building 1934 October (Othertype 10)
  - Certificate, with pen used by Franklin Delano Roosevelt in signing a crime bill 1934 May (Othertype 10)
  - Certificate of Homer Stille Cummings' recommendation re: prescription by Supreme Court of uniform rules of Criminal procedure, and the pen Franklin Delano Roosevelt used to sign the act of authorization 1938 June (Othertype 10)
  - Certificate given to Homer Stille Cummings from the staff of hte Bureau of War Risk Litigation 1939 January (Othertype 10)
  - Certificate re: Homer Stille Cummings' recommendation on independent control of the Federal Judiciary of its own budget and administration, and pen Franklin Delano Roosevelt used to enact this 1939 August (Othertype 10)
- SERIES XIX: MOTION PICTURE FILMS, NOTE: In January, 1980, the following newsreels were copied onto one 16 mm film [F-24] and the originals were destroyed. Running time: ca. 15 minutes.
  - "SPURS FINGERPRINT DRIVE" (Paramount News) [ca. 1934], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    "New York--A Rockefeller's prints go on record -- Attorney General Cummings, in Washington, urges public support."
  - "CLEAN UP TEXAS GANG!" (Paramount News) [1934], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    "Dallas -- 22 nabbed by U.S. agents for aiding southwest desperado Clyde Barrow, slain in gunfight last May."
  - "RACKET EXPOSE STUNS N.Y." (Paramount News) [ca. 1934], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    "New York -- Gangster income from policy racket shown to be 200 million yearly! Sensational expose uncovers nation-wide scandal."
  - "AMERICAN LEGION ON PARADE" (Pathe News) [ca. 1935], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
  - "NEWS FLASHES" (unidentified) (Pathe News) [ca. 1935], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    [Ceremony establishing a "Univesity of Crime"]
  - "OPEN JUSTICE BUILDING" (Paramount News) [1935-1936], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    "Washington -- President at dedication of Department's new $11,000,000 home! Attorney General Cummings and S[cott] M[arion] Loftin, Bar Association Head, Speak."
  - "PICKED POLICE STUDY UNDER U.S. EXPERTS" [in Washington, DC] (Paramount News" [ca. 1936], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
  - "U.S. READY TO SMASH POULTRY RACKETEERS" [in New York City] (Paramount News) [ca. 1936], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
  - Untitled. [Seconding speech at Presidential nominating convention] (Universal News Service) [1936], 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
  - Untitled. [Military award ceremony] 1933, 35 mm black-and-white nitrate film with sound
    Installation of Edward A. Hayes as Commander of the American Legion
- SERIES XX: CASED PHOTOGRAPHS ca. 1850-1870
  - Uriah Cummings (Father of Homer Stille Cummings) at 21 years of age [1854], Ambrotype (mother-of-pearl case) (Othertype 95-97, Item 103)
  - Uriah Cummings (Father of Homer Stille Cummings) at 17 years of age [1850], Daguerreotype (mother-of-pearl case) (Othertype 95-97, Item 104)
  - Uriah Cummings (Father of Homer Stille Cummings) with violin at 19 years of age [1852], Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 105)
  - Uriah and Audie Cummings (Homer Stille Cummings' parents) 1868, Tintype (Othertype 95-97, Item 106)
  - Audelia Lawrence Weekes (Stille) (Homer Stille Cummings' maternal grandmother) n.d., Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 107)
  - Jacob Schuyler Stille (Homer Stille Cummings' maternal grandfather) n.d., Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 108)
  - Arny Smith Ostram (Homer Stille Cummings' great-grandmother) with Audie Schuyler Stille (Homer Stille Cummings' mother) at 3 years of age [1850], Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 109)
  - Dewitt Clinton Stille (Homer Stille Cummings' great uncle) with Audie Schuyler Stille (Homer Stille Cummings' mother) at 8 years of age [1855], Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 110)
  - Nelson Stille (Homer Stille Cummings' great-uncle) n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 111)
  - Emma Barton Ba[rnes] (half sister to Homer Stille Cummings' maternal grandmother) [at 18 years of age] n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 112)
  - Elwood Fleet Doty (son of Harriet Weekes Doty) n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 113)
  - Unidentified woman n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 114)
  - Unidentified man n.d., Daguerreotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 115)
  - Unidentifiedsoldier n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 116)
  - Unidentified man n.d., Ambrotype (Othertype 95-97, Item 117)
- SERIES XXI: PHONOGRAPH RECORDINGS 1920-1953
  - Homer Cummings addresses entitled "Summons to Duty" and "President Wilson," delivered at the Democratic National Convention in San Francisco. Part of the nation's Forum series recorded by Columbia Gramaphone. 1920 June 28 (Othertype P. 493)
  - William Howard Taft addresses entitled "Democratic Policy Prevents Restoration of Prosperity." Victor Record [1920] (Othertype P. 494)
  - William Jennings Bryan address entitled "The Tariff Question." Victor Record [1920?] (Othertype P. 495)
  - President Roosevelt radio "Fireside Chat." Transcroption by the Radio and Film Methods Corporation 1935 April 28 (Othertype P. 496)
  - President Roosevelt "Bonus Speech." Radio and Film Methods Corporation transcription. 1935 May 22 (Othertype P. 497)
  - "March on with Roosevelt." Words and music by Gene Dabney, National Recording 1936 (Othertype P. 498)
  - Homer Cummings address (?) at the Democratic National Convention. Audio-Scriptions Recording, Slides 1 and 3. 1936 June 26 (Othertype P. 499-a)
  - Homer Cummings address (?) at the Democratic National Convention. Audio-Scriptions Recording, Slides 2 and 4. 1936 June 26 (Othertype P. 499-b)
  - Farewell message of King Edward VIII. Recording by Kugel Advertising Services. 1936 December 11 (Othertype P. 500)
  - Homer Cummings address entitled "Reorganizing the Courts." Audio-Scriptions, sides 1 and 3. 1937 February 14 (Othertype P. 501-a)
  - Homer CUmmings address entitled "Reorganizing the Courts." Audio-Scriptions Recording, sides 2 and 4. 1937 February 14 (Othertype P. 501-b)
  - Homer Cummings address entitled "The Second Chance." WSSR transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut, parts 1 and 3. 1944 November 5 (Othertype P. 502-a)
  - Homer Cummings address entitled "The Second Chance." WSSR transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut, parts 2 and 4. 1944 November 5 (Othertype P. 502-b)
  - Homer Cummings address entitled "The Eve of Victory." WSSR transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut, parts 1 and 3. 1944 November 6 (Othertype P. 503-a)
  - Homer Cummings address entitled "The Eve of Victory." WSSR transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut, parts 2 and 4. 1944 November 6 (Othertype P. 503-b)
  - The Hyde Park Service for President Roosevelt, as described by Bankhage over the Blue network, American Broadcasting Company. 1945 April 15 (Othertype P. 504)
  - Homer Cummings address (?) at the Connecticut Democratic State Central Committee. WSTC transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut. Parts A and C. 1946 November 2 (Othertype P. 505-a)
  - Homer Cummings address (?) at the Connecticut Democratic State Central Committee. WSTC transcription service, Stamford, Connecticut. Parts B and D. 1946 November 2 (Othertype P. 505-b)
  - "Boomerang," by the Screen Guild Players. Reference Recording, Washington, DC. Parts 1 and 5. 1947 November 10 (Othertype P. 506-a)
  - "Boomerang," by the Screen Guild Players. Reference Recording, Washington, DC. Parts 2 and 6. 1947 November 10 (Othertype P. 506-b)
  - "Boomerang," by the Screen Guild Players. Reference Recording, Washington, DC. Parts 3 and 7. 1947 November 10 (Othertype P. 506-c)
  - "Boomerang," by the Screen Guild Players. Reference Recording, Washington, DC. Parts 4 and 8. 1947 November 10 (Othertype P. 506-d)
  - Address by Homer Cummings for U.S. Senator Brien McMahon, Sound Studios Recording, Washington, DC 1950 October 30 (Othertype P. 507)
  - "The Spirit of Burning Tree." An informal talk by Merle Thorpe on the occasion of the 1953 Harvest Home Dinner. REcorded by the Burning Tree Club. 1953 (Othertype P. 508)
  - Untitled recording by Speak-O-Phone, Inc. n.d. (Othertype P. 509)
  - Unlabled recording by Audio-Scriptions. n.d. (Othertype P. 510)
  - Unlabled recording by Audio-Scriptions. n.d. (Othertype P. 511)
  - Unlabled recording by Audio-Scriptions. n.d. (Othertype P. 512)
  - Untitled transcription, manufactured by Presto, USA n.d. (Othertype P. 513)
  - Untitled transcription, manufactured by Presto, USA n.d. (Othertype P. 514)